Guide to the Tom Rankin photographs and papers, 1980-2013 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Tom Rankin photographs and papers 1980-2013 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Rankin, Tom
31.5 Linear Feet 13,606 Items
Documentary photographer, filmmaker, folklorist, professor of art and documentary studies, and former director of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University.
The photographic work of Tom Rankin in this collection dates from 1980 to 2008, and consists of black-and-white gelatin silver and chromogenic color photographs documenting the American South, particularly religious sites, rituals, and communities in the Mississippi Delta region, but also individuals and landscapes from other locations in the South. Images often feature churches and cemeteries. One body of photographs features a series of portraits of Mississippi writer Larry Brown. Finished prints measure 11x14 and 16x20 inches, with some housed in mats. Along with the finished large-format prints, there are also 8x10 inch black-and-white matted contact prints. There is also a digital audio recording of a talk by Rankin at the exhibit opening of his work, Near the Cross: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta. A large addition to the collection consists of manuscript materials and two film reels deriving from Rankin's career and art practice, and dates from approximately 1980 to 2013. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, publication and commercial use requires the permission of the photographer.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Tom Rankin photographs and papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift and purchase from 2007 to 2013.
Biographical Note
Tom Rankin served as the Director of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University for three consecutive five-year terms until 2013, and is a Professor of the Practice in the Arts at Duke University. A documentary photographer, filmmaker, writer, editor, and folklorist, he has been documenting and interpreting American culture, particularly in the South, for nearly twenty years. His photographic work has been published and widely exhibited. His most long-standing work has been to reveal through the documentary arts the culture and society of the Mississippi Delta region, where he has also served as a faculty member of Delta State University and the University of Mississippi. He has returned many times since the 1980s to photograph the landscapes and people of the Mississippi Delta, most recently in 2011 after the great floods of that year. His books include Sacred Space: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta (1993), which received the Mississippi Institute of Arts and Letters Award for Photography, 'Deaf Maggie Lee Sayre': Photographs of a River Life(1995), Faulkner's World: The Photographs of Martin J. Dain (1997), and Local Heroes Changing America: Indivisible (2000). He received an MFA from Georgia State University and an MA from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. American Photo Magazine named Tom Rankin as one of the 100 Most Important People in Photography, May, 2005.
Collection Overview
The photographic work of Tom Rankin in this collection dates from 1980 to 2008, and consists of black-and-white gelatin silver and chromogenic color photographs from Rankin's work documenting the American South, particularly religious sites, rituals, and communities in the Mississippi Delta region, but also individuals and landscapes from other locations in the South. Images often feature churches and cemeteries. One body of photographs features a series of portraits of Mississippi writer Larry Brown. Finished prints measure 11x14 and 16x20 inches, with some housed in mats. Along with the finished large-format prints, there are also 8x10 inch black-and-white matted contact prints. All titles are original as designated by the photographer.
Supporting materials include a digital audio recording of a talk by Rankin at the exhibit opening of his work, Near the Cross: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta. A selection of Rankin's photographs was published in Sacred Space: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta, 1993. All titles are original as designated by the photographer. Some dates refer to printing dates rather than the date image was taken. An addition to the collection (2013-0114) (13,500 items, 22.5 lin. ft.) consists of manuscript materials related to Tom Rankin's career and art practice, including book publications and book dummies. Also includes two film reels.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.
Collection Arrangement
The photographic materials are arranged alphabetically by the title of the body of work: Larry Brown; Near the Cross: Mississippi Delta; Portraits of the American South; and Sacred Space. These are followed by Other Work, and Other Materials. Within project series, prints are in order as received from the photographer. The papers are currently unprocessed.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Rankin, Tom
Brown, Larry, 1951-2004
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies
African Americans -- Mississippi
Documentary photographers -- North Carolina
Documentary photography -- United States
Mississippi -- Pictorial works
Mississippi -- Religious life
Mississippi -- Social life and customs
Religion -- Pictorial works
Southern States -- Pictorial works
Black-and-white photographs
Color photographs
Contact prints
Gelatin silver prints
Digital inkjet prints
Documentaries (motion picture genre)
mp3 files
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
Contents of Collection
- Larry Brown, 1993-1996 and undated, (20 prints)
  Black-and-white gelatin silver and digital or chromogenic (C print) color portraits of Mississippi writer Larry Brown with his family and friends in Mississippi. Prints vary in size from 11x14" to 16x10" and are signed by the photographer. Arranged in original order as received.
  - Larry Brown on porch swing at Jefferson Ave., Oxford, 1993, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Seated outside with jars in foreground, Tula, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Wearing white tee shirt holding Lilly (puppy dog), (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larry and Mary Annie on grass, 1993, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larry Brown riding and playing guitar, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larry wearing dark button down shirt standing in front of vines, 1996, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larry and Charlie Jacobs with boat on bank, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larry at Charlie Jacobs funeral, Bolivar County, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larry resting on hoe in garden, Oxford, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larry Brown and Richard Howorth from behind, (digital color print, 13x16" ) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Larry Brown and Richard Howorth, (digital color print, 13x16" ) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Blue striped shirt, (chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Larry cleaning Shane's deer, Yocana, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Larry with beer and cigarette looking up, Oxford, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Larry burning, 1993, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Larry shirtless leaning on fence post, Tula, 1993, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Larry and Mary Annie fishing, Tula, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Larry Brown and Johnny Miles smoking, Copiah County, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Larry Brown with rack of horns, Copiah County, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Larry Brown in doorway of shed, Oxford, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Near the Cross: Mississippi Delta, late 1980s-early 1990s, (27 prints)
  Black-and-white gelatin silver prints document and reflect on spiritual and religious practices in the Mississippi Delta region of the Southern United States. Dominant subjects include churches, individuals associated with the churches, cemetery sites, and baptisms. All prints measure 11x14 inches. Arranged in original order as received. All titles are original.
  - Mt. Tinna M. B. Church, Scott, 1990 (NOTE: these prints are in fact not in box 1) (Box 1, Folder ?)
  - Bethlehem No. 2 M. B. Church, Shaw, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder ?)
  - Campbellsville Church, Holly Bluff, 2007, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Candidate for baptism, fourth week in August, Perthshire, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baptism, Jerusalem M. B. Church, Mound Bayou, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Candidate for baptism, Mound Bayou, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Handmade gravestones, Mound Bayou, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mt. Pleasant M. B. Church, Beulah, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Church on Deer Creek, Estill, Mississippi, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reverend E. B. Brown, Mt. Pleasant M. B. Church, Beulah, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bethlehem No. 2 M. B. Church, Shaw, 1992, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - St. James Missionary Baptist Church, Jonestown, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Near Litton, Mississippi, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abundant Life Church, Lamont, 2007, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brooks Chapel M. B. Church, Greenwood, 2006, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Congregation outside Bethlehem No. 2 M. B. Church, Shaw, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reverend Tom Bronner with neighborhood children, Gunnison, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New Hope Church, Shelby, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hand-painted window, A. M. E. Church, Indianola, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Grave of Alfred Green, Morning Star Cemetery, Beulah, 2006, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Paper Easter flowers, near Tchula, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Near Shaw, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mt. Olive Church, Bolivar County, 1992, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Deacon Fred Davis, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baptism of Cheronda Brown by Reverend Crabtree, Stamps Lake, Perthshire, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baptism, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Prayer after baptism, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Portraits of The American South, late 1990s-early 1990s, (25 prints)
  Images of individuals, cemeteries, businesses, and landscapes taken by Rankin in various Southern states, including Alabama, Georgia, Mississippi, and Virginia. Includes vintage chromogenic prints and black-and-white gelatin silver prints, ranging in size from 11x14 inches to 16x20 inches, with some black-and-white prints in mats. Some prints are signed by the photographer. Arranged in original order as received. All titles are original.
  - Sonny Boy Williamson's grave, Tutwiler, Mississippi, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Barbershop, Columbus, Mississippi, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dairy Freeze, Crystal Springs, Mississippi, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oakly and Manuel under wisteria, Sunflower, Mississippi, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Krispy Kreme Christmas window, Atlanta, Georgia, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Rice's Cross Garden, Prattville, Alabama, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - White Castle, Meridian, Mississippi, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Monument, Appomattox, Virginia, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Baseball concession stands, Baker County, Georgia, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - My job work day and night, Mary T. Smith, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scarecrow, Mary T. Smith, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - (Interior) W. C. Rice's Chapel, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - (Vertical) Manuel and wisteria, Sunflower, Mississippi, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - (The South) North of Shaw, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Holly Bluff, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - (The South) Margaret's Gro & Mkt, Vicksburg, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Man in heavy coat next to portable b/w tv, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Man in check shirt and pants smoking cigarette, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Man wearing a dark fedora, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Man standing in front of a highly polished sports car, NC, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Man holding two hounds on a leash, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Man sitting in back of a boat near the motor, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Close-up of a man playing guitar close to his chest, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Man leaning on a fishing boat wearing "CAT" cap, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Man holding a banjo on porch with three cats, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inches mat ) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Sacred Space, 1993, (65 prints)
  This body of work comprises 11x14 inches black-and-white gelatin silver prints, some in 16x20 inches mats; 16x20 inches gelatin silver prints in 20x24" mats; vintage 16x20 inches chromogenic color prints; and 8x10" black-and-white contact prints in 11x14 inches mats. Many prints are signed by the photographer. All locations are in Mississippi. Arranged in original order as received. All titles are original.
  - Rev. Brooks Tobe with dog, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rev. Bronner in church with his niece, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Three at a time, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baptism, Jerusalem M. B. Church, Mound Bayou, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Deacon Fred Davis, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Three young girls being baptized in Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 11x14 inches ) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Olive Church, Bolivar County, 1992, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rev. Tom Bronner with neighborhood children, Gunnison, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Matilda Wray grave, near Shaw, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - New Hope Church, Shelby, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hand painted window, A. M. E. Church, Indianola, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Pleasant M. B. Church, Beulah, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bethlehem No. 2 M. B. Church, Shaw, 1992, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rev. E. B. Brown, Mt. Pleasant M. B. Church, Beulah, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Handmade gravestones, Mound Bayou, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Paper Easter flowers, near Tchula, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 8x10" in 11x14 inches mat ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Graves with flowers, Sunflower County, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Church in field, near Litton, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - A stained glass window of three wise men, Indianola, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - (Interior) New Hope Church, Shelby, 1989, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - (Exterior) Stained glass windows, Indianola, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Church Street, Indianola, (vintage chromogenic color print, 16x20 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Matilda Wray grave, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - (Exterior) Four hand painted church windows, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Jesus is our Saviour, steeple at Margaret's market, Vicksburg, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - (Interior) Two hand painted church windows, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Propane tank Highway 61, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Evening Star Baptist Church, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cotton, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Particle board church, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rev. Tobe on porch, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Tinna M. B. Church, Scott, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - New Hope Church, Shelby, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - White church, double white doors, electric line cutting through picture, propane tank on side, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - (Interior) Church with dark paneling and carpet, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Shellmound, Mississippi, 1991 (white frame church with shadow of tree), (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - C.A. Burke Memorial M. B. Church, Rosedale, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Tinna M.B. Church, near Scott, 2007, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Tinna M.B. Church, near Scott, 2007, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Little Ebenezer Baptist Church, Rosedale, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ida Woodruff grave, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Paper Easter flowers, near Tchula, Mississippi, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rev. Tom Bronner with neighborhood children, Gunnison, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rev. E. B. Brown at pulpit, Mt. Pleasant M. B. Church, Beulah, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Graves of Charley Bains and Alfred Green, Beulah, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 16x20 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Grave of Alfred Green, Morning Star Cemetery, Beulah, 2006, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bethlehem No. 2 M. B. Church, Shaw, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Man in striped suspenders standing in doorway., (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Brooks Chapel M. B. Church, Greenwood, 2006, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - St. James Missionary Baptist Church, Jonestown, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Abundant Life Church, Lamont, 2007, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Campbellsville Church, Holly Bluff, 2007, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Near Litton, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24 inch mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Deteriorating church in overgrowth across dirt road from field, puddles in road, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24" mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Church on Deer Creek, Estill, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 16x20 inches in 20x24" mat ) (Box 6, Folder 1)